Inventory of the Kingsley Davis Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- "Latin America's Multiplying Peoples," Foreign Affairs, 1947 July. (Folder 48: 6)
- "Final Note on a Case of Extreme Isolation," American Journal of Sociology, 1947 March. (Folder 48: 7)
- "Differential Fertility in Puerto Rico," co-authored with Jerry W. Combs, Jr., Population Studies, 1951 November. (Folder 48: 8)
- "The Sociology of an Aging Population," co-authored with Jerry W. Combs, Jr., Social and Biological Challenge of Our Aging Population, 1950. (Folder 48: 9)
- "Population and the Further Spread of Industrial Society," paper, Symposium on Problems of Development of Densely Settled Areas, Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, 1951 February. (Folder 48: 10)
- "The Pattern of Puerto Rican Fertility," Population Studies, 1951 March. (Folder 48: 11)
- "Fertility Control and the Demographic Transition in India," paper, Interrelations of Demographic, Economic, and Social Problems in Selected Underdeveloped Areas, Proceedings of the Annual Conference, 1953. (Folder 48: 12)
- "Future Population Trends and their Significance," paper, Eighteenth North American Wildlife Conference, Wildlife Management Institute, Washington, D.C., 1953 March 9-11. (Folder 48: 13)
- "Institutional Patterns Favoring High Fertility in Underdeveloped Areas," Eugenics Quarterly, 1955 March. (Folder 48: 14)
- "The World Institution of Urbanization," co-authored with Hilda Hertz, Bulletin of the International Statistical Institute, 1954. (Folder 48: 15)
- "Urbanization and the Development of Pre-Industrial Areas," Economic Development and Cultural Change, 1954 October. (Folder 48: 16)
- "Internal Migration and Urbanization in Relation to Economic Development,", 1955. (Folder 48: 17)
- Correspondence (Box 49)
  - 1962 July - December (Folder 49: 1-6)
  - 1963 January - March (Folder 49: 7-9)
- Industrial Urbanization--miscellaneous, 1959-1960. (Folder 49: 10)
- Tenure meeting for Nathan Glazer and others, 1963 (Folder 49: 11)
- Correspondence, 1955-1958 (Folder 49: 12-13)
- "Population Policy and International Changes," draft 1, copy 2, undated. (Box-folder 50: 1)
- Writings, "Population Policy and International Change.", undated (Folder 50: 2-4)
  Typescript manuscripts (multiple copies),
- Correspondence, 1961 July (Folder 50: 5)
- "Population Essays," co-authored with Judith Blake, undated (Box 51)
  - Typescript, chapters I, II, and V (Folder 51: 1)
  - Copies of Chapter I (Folder 51 :2)
  - Copies of Chapter II (Folder 51: 3)
  - Copies of Chapter V (Folder 51: 4)
- Kingsley Davis manuscripts. (Folder 51: 5-6)
- "International Relations and Population Policy." (Folder 51: 7)
- "Adolescent Pregnancy and Fertility." (Folder 51: 8)
- "The Urbanization of Human Population,", 1965-1973. (Box-folder 52: 1)
  Includes a printed copy, Scientific American, 1965 September; printed copy in Spanish, Universitas, 1973 January 18 and 25; and a printed copy in Chinese, 1966
- "Urbanization in India: Past and Future,", undated. (Folder 52: 2)
  Typescript manuscript
- Books received, 1976-1977 (Folder 52: 3)
- Reprint requests, 1975-1976 (Folder 52: 4)
- Reviews of others' manuscripts, undated (Folder 52: 5)
- Reviews of Kingsley Davis's publications (alphabetical), 1973-1975 (Folder 52: 6)
- Correspondence
  - Reprint series and catalogue--Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1972 (Folder 52: 7)
  - Editorial Boards, 1972-1975 (Folder 52: 8)
  - Publishers, 1972-1977 (Folder 52: 9)
  - Article, "Zero Population Growth," Daedalus, 1973 (Folder 52: 10)
  - Authors, 1973-1974 (Folder 52: 11)
- Projected volume on population policy with notes from J. Seibert, 1950-1974 (Box-folder 53: 1)
- Population, 1975-1976 (Folder 53: 2-3)
- Bahrain letter, 1978-1980 (Folder 53: 4)
- Africa trip, 1952 (Box 54)
  - Africa trip (Box-folder 54: 1)
  - Letters and clippings (Folder 54: 2-3)
- "The Origin and Growth of Urbanization in the World," American Journal of Sociology, 1955 March. (Folder 54: 4)
- "The Unpredicted Pattern of Population Change," Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1956 May. (Folder 54: 5)
- "Social Structure and Fertility: An Analytic Framework," co-authored with Judith Blake, Economic Development and Cultural Change, 1956 April. (Folder 54: 6)
  Printed copy. Includes a typescript copy in Spanish
- "The Process of Urbanization in India, 1901-1951: A Study Based on Indian Census Statistics," a dissertation presented to the University of Delhi in candidacy for the degree of the Doctor of Philosophy, by Ashish Bose, 1959. (Folder 54: 7)
- "The Population Specter: Rapidly Declining Death Rate in Densely Populated Countries, the Amazing Decline of Mortality in Underdeveloped Areas," American Economic Review, 1956 May. (Folder 54: 8)
- Correspondence
  - 1963 May – June (Folder 54: 9-10)
  - M--Miscellaneous, 1949-1955 (Folder 54: 11-12)
- "Metropolitan Areas without Growth," report, Edgar Rust, 1974 November 1 (Box-folder 55: 1)